

Kamil Szczepanik

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kamilszczepanik/ Email: kszczepanikcontact@gmail.com Based in: Dubai, UAE Github: https://github.com/kamilszczepanik Portfolio: https://bit.ly/kamil-szczepanik-portfolio Phone: + 971544099548

Software Developer with almost 5 years of professional experience creating frontend, backend and mobile systems. Passionate about system design and solving scalability issues, with a desire to develop further in that direction. Into startups and padel off-hours.

SKILLS

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, Java

Developer's Tools GIT, Docker, Agile, PostgreSQL, SQLite, AI(ChatGPT, Github Copilot), CMS, CI/CD, AWS, GCP

Software/Frameworks React, Remix, NextJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Redux Toolkit & Query, Prisma, Django, Tailwind, Material UI,

Vue, Pinia, FastAPI, Jira, Vitest, Postman, WS, MongoDB, Playwright, RTL, Figma, Ant Design, Shadon UI

Others Leadership, Strategic Planning, Communication, Problem-solving, Architecture, UX/UI, REST, SSR, SPA

Attention to details, SEO, Web Security/Performance/Accessibility

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INRA - Independent Ranking - Dubai, UAE

Jun. 2024 - Present

Full Stack Developer - Typescript, React, NodeJS, Remix, NextJS, Prisma, SQLite, Vue, Pinia:

- [freelance] Done 10+ projects, building scalable apps with modern UI/UX, boosting engagement and performance.
- [consulting] Advised 30+ clients incl. C-level execs, on IT strategy, architecture, scaling, optimizing costs, delivery.
- [project] Build a platform to discover, compare, and share the best products, leading from idea to MVP.

SKY ENGINE AI Ltd. - London, United Kingdom

Lead Frontend Developer - Typescript, React, Redux Toolkit, Jira, Scrum, CR:

Feb. 2023 - Jun. 2024

- Led 7 web projects, focusing on quality and team efficiency. Managed all environments and releases.
- Established the whole team culture including effective meetings, strategic planning, constructive feedback.
- Done 15+ user testing sessions to gather feedback, employees onboardings, internal training sessions.

Full Stack Developer – Typescript, React, Python, Django, Redux Toolkit & Query:

May 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Redesigned and refactored a platform for synthetic data in VR, focusing on best practices.
- Built authentication, user management, platform management, CMS and design systems from scratch.
- Wrote 150+ unit, integration, and end-to-end tests and defined 100+ test cases for the QA team.
- Implemented email systems and upgraded legacy code, improving performance and scalability.

Unity-t Ltd. - Warsaw, Poland

Full Stack Developer – Typescript, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS:

Sep. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Developed an interface for automated testing systems, enabling manual testers to run and manage tests.
- Integrated the testing system to the existing internal system. Used best practices in React and Node JS.
- Designed and implemented API, backend and database for the testing system.

Automation Tester – Typescript, Selenium, Bash, Git:

Jun. 2021 - Sep. 2021

- Developed 70+ automated test cases using TypeScript & Selenium, improving UX, quality & performance.
- Improved test efficiency by 5x using Bash scripting, improved every single test speed by more than 25%.
- Architectured a testing system, made multiple decisions that heavily impacted company testing practices.

Manual Tester – Postman, JUnit, Jira, Excel:

May 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Initiated API testing script using JUnit for releases and data migration, added 30+ API test cases.
- Communication with developers, testers, stakeholders, managing team. Giving and receiving feedback.
- Tested a system that prevented code with multiple bugs from going to production. Learned communication in IT.

EDUCATION

Attended Warsaw School of Information Technology (WIT)

Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2022

IT Management Techniques (Computer Science)

Technical College (ZSP1 Siedlce)

Oct. 2016 - Jun. 2020

IT Specialist